Guide to the Deep Sea Fishermen's Union of the Pacific Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- Deep Sea Fishermen's Union of the Pacific records, 1890-2019; 6144-002; 6.49 cubic feet 7 boxes 7 boxes; 0.425 GB 3 CDs
  - HISTORICAL REFERENCE FILES, 1890-2012; SERIES 7 (Box-folder 4/9-4/53, 5/1-5/41, 6/1-6/3)
    - Interviews, 1985-2015; Subseries A (Box-folder 4/9-4/13)
      - Transcript from Interview with Cliff Swendsen, approximately 1985-1995 (Box-folder 4/10)
      - Ness and Borge interview by Jeffrey Kahrs and Jan Standaert, 2012 (Box-folder 4/11)
      - Thorkildsen Family Interview by Jeffrey Kahrs and Jan Standaert, 2012 (Box-folder 4/12)
      - Barney Olsen and Tem Henkel Interview with Jeff Kahrs, approximately 2000-2010 (Box-folder 4/13)
    - Photographs, 1910-2011; Subseries B (Box-folder 4/14-4/31)
      - Photograph Copies - Halibut Schooners, approximately 1910-1920 (Box-folder 4/14)
      - Photographs of Fishing Vessel Woniya and Crew, approximately 2003; 1 5x7 color print; 5 3 x 5 color prints; 1 4 x 6 color print (Box-folder 4/15)
      - Fishing Vessel Evening Star Crew Photograph, 2011; black and white photocopy (Box-folder 4/16)
      - Fishing Vessel Aleutian Photographs, approximately 1930; photocopies (Box-folder 4/17)
      - Fishing Vessel Carol M Crew Photographs, 1995; 3 4x6 color prints (Box-folder 4/18)
      - Photograph of Jay Brevik, approximately 1980-1990; 1 3.25 x 6 color print (Box-folder 4/19)
      - Photographs - Union Meeting of March 14, 2000 and Memorial for David Taylor, 14 4x6 color prints (Box-folder 4/20)
      - Fishing Vessel Aleutian and Fish Expo Photographs, 2003; 28 4x6 color prints (Box-folder 4/21)
      - Fishing Vessel Photographs, 1969 - approximately 1995; 23 color prints (Box-folder 4/22)
      - Fishermen's Terminal Fall Festival Photographs, 1990-2003; 7 4x6 color prints (Box-folder 4/23)
      - Fish Expo and Marketing Event Photographs, 1994-1996; 17 4x6 color prints (Box-folder 4/24)
      - Blessing of the Fleet Photographs, 1998; 10 3.5x5 color prints (Box-folder 4/25)
      - Office Staff Photographs, approximately 1990-2000; 3 5x7 color prints (Box-folder 4/26)
      - Deep Sea Fishermen's Union Party Photographs, 1983-1988; 16 3x5 color prints (Box-folder 4/27)
      - Flat Fish Ball Photographs, 1992; 30 4x6 color prints (Box-folder 4/28)
      - Deep Sea Fishermen's Union Party Photographs, approximately 1990-1995; 28 color prints (Box-folder 4/29)
      - Flat Fish Ball Photographs, 1996; 23 4x6 color prints (Box-folder 4/30)
      - Union Event Photographs, approximately 1960-2000; 10 color prints; 1 8x10 black and white print (Box-folder 4/31)
    - Secondary Accounts, 1940-2012; Subseries C (Box-folder 4/32-5/2)
      - Betty Annette Lowman. "I Went Halibut Fishing", 1940 (Box-folder 4/32)
      - Ralph Chipman. "The Last Trip of the Scandia", approximately 1950-1966 (Box-folder 4/33)
      - "Halibut: A Fishery in Critical Focus" (Pacific Fisherman Magazine Article), 1963 (Box-folder 4/34)
      - Notes on Halibut Fishery History, approximately 1970 (Box-folder 4/35)
      - A.K. Larssen and Sig Jaeger. "The ABC's of Fo'c'sle Living", 1976 (Box-folder 4/36)
      - Sverre Arestad. "Norwegians in the West Coast Fisheries", 1985 (Box-folder 4/37)
      - Jan Standaert Notes on Halibut Industry History, 2002-2012 (Box-folder 4/38)
      - 90th Anniversary Materials, 2002 (Box-folder 4/39)
      - Jeff Kahrs. "A Short History of the Deep Sea Fishermen's Union of the Pacific", 1993 (Box-folder 4/40)
      - Jeff Kahrs. "Jimmy Clarke, Longliner: Still Fishin' After All Those Years", 1993 (Box-folder 4/41)
      - The Cruise of the Chelsea (A Toast), approximately 2000s (Box-folder 4/42)
      - Deep Sea Fishermen's Union History House Project, 2006 (Box-folder 4/43)
      - Sharing a Short History of Our Union, 2011 (Box-folder 4/44)
      - Lokken Halibut Boat List, 2010 (Box-folder 4/45)
      - Ralph W. Andrews and A.K. Larssen. "Fish and Ships", 1959; Hardcover book (Box-folder 4/46)
      - Anton Jackson Membership Card and Documents, 1950-1977 (Box-folder 4/47)
      - Proceedings of First Annual Convention of United Fishermen's Union of the Pacific, 1938 (Box-folder 4/48)
      - Second Annual Convention of Federated Fishermen's Council, 1938 (Box-folder 4/49)
      - Betty A. Lowman Records of Fishermen's Unions, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 4/50)
      - Halibut Fishery Treaty Between U.S. And Canada, 1887-1945 (Box-folder 4/51)
      - Pacific Halibut Catch Statistics, 1916-1928 (Box-folder 4/52)
      - Halibut Industry Catch and Policy, 1905-1932 (Box-folder 4/53)
      - Halibut Industry Catch and Policy, 1932-1973 (Box-folder 5/1)
      - Chart of Historical Halibut Catch, 1970 (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Press Clippings, 1890-2019; Subseries D (Box-folder 5/3-6/3)
      - Gurdy Introduction, 1914-1916 (Box-folder 5/3)
      - Halibut Fishermen's Wives Association Press Clippings, 1955-1978 (Box-folder 5/4)
      - Beatrice "Betty" Annette Lowman, 1937-2012 (Box-folder 5/5)
      - Tom Samuelson Research on Betty Annette Lowman, 2011 (Box-folder 5/6)
      - Peggy Dyson, 2012 (Box-folder 5/7)
      - Schooner Albatross, 1911-1948 (Box-folder 5/8)
      - Schooner Helgeland, 1913-1941 (Box-folder 5/9)
      - Fishing Vessel Martindale, 1933-1969 (Box-folder 5/10)
      - Schooner Orient, 1913-1931 (Box-folder 5/11)
      - Schooner Panama, 1912-1930 (Box-folder 5/12)
      - Schooner Paragon, 1937-1971 (Box-folder 5/13)
      - Fishing Vessel Polaris, 1988 (Box-folder 5/14)
      - Schooner Siloam, 1910-1950 (Box-folder 5/15)
      - Schooner Thor, 1924-2012 (Box-folder 5/16)
      - Fishing the Thor, 3 copies video on DVD; running time 8:41 (Box-folder 5/17)
      - Schooner Vansee, 1914-1999 (Box-folder 5/18)
      - Halibut Fleet Press Clippings, 1890-1905 (Box-folder 5/19)
      - Halibut Fleet Press Clippings, 1906-1909 (Box-folder 5/20)
      - Halibut Fleet Press Clippings, 1910-1915 (Box-folder 5/21)
      - Halibut Fleet Press Clippings, 1916-1919 (Box-folder 5/22)
      - Halibut Fleet Press Clippings, 1920-1929 (Box-folder 5/23)
      - Halibut Fleet Press Clippings, 1930-1939 (Box-folder 5/24)
      - Halibut Fleet Press Clippings, 1956-1986 (Box-folder 5/25)
      - Articles on Halibut Fishing, 1980-2010 (Box-folder 5/26)
      - Blessing Seattle's Halibut Fleet, 1976 (Box-folder 5/27)
      - Seattle-Area Maritime Labor History Press Clippings, 1901-1939 (Box-folder 5/28)
      - Fishing Fleet Press Clippings, 1906-1949 (Box-folder 5/29)
      - Fishing Fleet Press Clippings, 1930-1987 (Box-folder 5/30)
      - Fishing Industry Press Clippings, 1981-1989 (Box-folder 5/31)
      - Fishing Industry Press Clippings, 1991-1999 (Box-folder 5/32)
      - Fishing Industry Press Clippings, 2000-2019 (Box-folder 5/33)
      - News Clippings: Copy of Alaska Fisherman's Journal Crew Photos, 1990 (Box-folder 5/34)
      - "Pacific Fishing" - February 2012 Issue (Box-folder 5/35)
      - Articles on Fishing Vessel Disasters and Sinkings, 1900-1923 (Box-folder 5/36)
      - Fishermen Lost at Sea, 1930-1939 (Box-folder 5/37)
      - Vessel Losses and Crew Deaths, 1892-1970 (Box-folder 5/38)
      - Fishermen's Memorial List, 1988 (Box-folder 5/39)
      - Extracts from "Canadian Fisherman" (magazine), 1915-1923 (Box-folder 5/40)
      - Pacific Fisherman (Magazine) Copies Related to Halibut Fishing, 1910-1919 (Box-folder 5/41)
      - Phil Jacobsen Scrapbook Copies, 1946-1986 (Box-folder 6/1)
      - Ruth Desrosier Scrapbook Copies, 1982-1992 (Box-folder 6/2)
      - Copies from Ivan Lund, 1973-1987 (Box-folder 6/3)
  - PUBLICATION RECORDS, 1992-2015; SERIES 8 (Box-folder 6/4-6/9)
    - 90th Anniversary History of Deep Sea Fishermen's Union, 1992 (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Anniversary Book -- draft, 2013 (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Anniversary Book -- Photos, 2013 (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Book "One Hook at a Time" Cost, Distribution, Pricing, 2012-2015 (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Artwork for "The Schooner", Other Publications, 2015 (Box-folder 6/8)
    - DSFU Calendar, 2002 (Box-folder 6/9)
  - ARTIFACTS, 1931-2010; SERIES 9 (Box-folder 6/10-6/13, 7/1-7/5)
    - Schooner Atlantic Pilot House Logs, 1931, 1933 (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Schooner Atlantic Pilot House Logs, 1934, 1936 (Box-folder 6/11)
    - Schooner Atlantic Pilot House Log, 1939 (Box-folder 6/12)
    - "I'm Hooked on Halibut" (Bumper Sticker), approximately 2000-2010 (Box-folder 6/13)
    - Mortuary Benefit Cards, 1949-1965; 4x6" cards arranged alphabetically (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Mortuary Fund Receipts, 1945-1948 (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Clarence Brevik Membership Book, 1949-1959 (Box-folder 7/3)
      SSN redacted
    - Clearance Record Book, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 7/4)
    - Clearance Cards, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 7/5)